MUHAMMAD MAHDI

(PREVIOUS NAME: SUZON CHANDRA DAS)

C/O: Mokaddes Ali, Enayet Fuskar Goli, Doniya, Jatrabari, Dhaka

Cell: 8801936583856, Email: suzon.du@hotmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/suzon-das-2b8112aa | https://github.com/suzondas

Accomplished software developer with 8 years of experience in development of applications. Excels in every stage of the life cycle of software development, including design creation, coding, debugging, testing, deployment and maintenance. Expert in devising innovative and tailored solutions to assist businesses achieve their goals in a variety of organizations. Advanced skills and knowledge of leading programming tools with a strong background in mathematics, algorithms, and data-processing logic.

EXPERIENCE

JUN 2017 - PRESENT

ASSISTANT PROGRAMMER, BANBEIS, MINISTRY OF EDUCATION, BANGALDESH.

Lead Web Application Developer using Laravel, CakePhp, Oracle DB, VueJs, Angularjs. Oracle Database Manager, Linux Server Manager, Application Deployment Manager.

Githubs: https://github.com/suzondas/sebabox, https://github.com/suzondas/sebabox, https://github.com/suzondas/make-api-view, https://github.com/BANBEIS/covid19-app

JULY 2017 – OCTOBER 2020 | PART TIME SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER, FITNESSPLUS GYM BANGLADESH

Total Gym Management Application Development using Cakephp, ZKTeco Attendance Management Solution (custom web application), Realtime Attendance Management using Python, Kivy, MySQL Githubs: https://github.com/suzondas/gym_soft_gulshan, https://github.com/suzondas/gym_soft_uttara, https://github.com/suzondas/tad-php-angularis, https://github.com/suzondas/ZKTeco-Realtime-with-Kivy

JULY 2015 - MAY 2017

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, AAN-NAHL SOFTWARE LTD.

Full Stack MEAN developer, CakePhp Developer

Languages: Nodejs, Expressjs, Sailsjs, Angualarjs, Angular 2, Mysql, Mongodb, Cakephp

SEPTEMBER 2014 – JUNE 2015

UGC-HEQEP SUB PROJECT MANAGER, SHER-E-BANGLA AGRICULTURAL UNIVERSITY

Debian server management, Web Service management, Koha installation and management, Dspace installation and management

Links: http://opac.saulibrary.edu.bd | http://opac.saulibrary.edu.bd | http://www.saulibrary.edu.bd | http://www.saulibrary.edu.bd | http://www.saulibrary.edu.bd<

EDUCATION

2019

PGD IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY,

JAHANGIRNAGAR UNIVERSITY

CGPA: 3.79 out of 4

2011

BACHELOR(HONOURS) IN INFORMATION SCIENCE AND LIBRARY MANAGEMENT,

UNIVERSITY OF DHAKA

CGPA: 3.57 out of 4

CERTIFICATION

2021

Certificate Course on Web Application Development with Laravel, VueJS, Oracle

Arranged by: IBCS Primax, Bangladesh

Duration: 14 Days

2020

Oracle Certified Professional (OCP) 12C/19C: Database Administration Course

Arranged by: IBCS Primax, Bangladesh

Duration: 6 Months

2019

Education using ICT Technologies

Arranged by: NIPA, Ministry of Science, ICT and Future Planning, South Korea

Duration: 14 Days

2018

Certified ScrumMaster®, Certified Scrum Developer®

Arranged by: ScrumAlliance.org

2012

Web Design and Application Design

Arranged by: Bangladesh-Korea Information Access Center, Department of CSE, BUET

Duration: 3 Months

SKILLS

Language/TOOLS

Framework

	Laravel CakePhp
DUD	Lataver Caker iip
PHP	ExpressJS SailsJS Socket.io
NODEJS	
1100230	VanillaJS AngularJS VueJS JQuery
JAVASCRIPT	
	Kivy Django
PYTHON	
	Aamazon Web Service Digital Ocean Physical Machine
DEPLOYMENT	
	Linux-Centos, Debian, Ubuntu
OS	Microsoft Server – 2019, 2016
	MongoDB, Oracle 11g, 12C, MySQL, PostgreSQL
DATABASE	
	GIT
VERSION CONTROL	
SYSTEM	PhpStorm, Webstorm, PyCharm
IDE	MS Visual Code, SublimeText
IDE	Asana MS Team Trello
TEAM	Asana Wis Team Treno
COLLABORATION	
	UXPin MockFlow
UI DESIGN	
	NPM Composer BOWER
DEPENDENCY	
MANAGER	
	GULP GRUNT
TASK RUNNER	
	Webpack Browserify
MODULE BUNDLER	

ACTIVITIES

I have been loving programming since 2004 when I was 16. I Started programming using Visual Basic 6. Then I started Web Programming in 2008 using PHP, MySql, Ajax. In 2009 I developed some educational applications using .Net. I developed some faculty websites for Dhaka University in 2010. In 2010 I learnt Perl for contributing to Open-Source Library Management System koha (https://koha-community.org). In 2014 I participated in National Hackathon Program and koha Bugzilla program. I started my career as a Software Engineer in 2015 in a Software Company where I was lead in Linkdensity and SEO Intelligence Agency project. These are SEO Testing Platforms developed by CakePhp. Then I was assigned to NodeJS based "SOCHARA" Project. It was a Californian Client funded big project which was designed to integrate Social Platforms from Single Point. Features were- Calendar, Emails, Notes, Dashboard, Posts, Chats, Event Generations and Management, Label and Card Generation, etc. After successfully completing the Project, I joined in a Prominent Gymnasium Company as a Senior Software Engineer. There I developed a Total Gym Management Solution. The solution includes different modules i.e.- Member and Staff Management, Subscription Fee Management, Booking & Scheduling, Attendance Management (Integrated with Zkteco Attendance Machine), Membership Management, Invoice and Report Generation, etc. using CakePhp, MySQL, AngularJS and this solution was deployed in paid Digital Ocean Server. I also developed Real Time Attendance system for watching Entry and Exit of Members into/from the Gymnasium along with their Basic Information, Entry/Exit Time, Membership Type, Expire Date and Payment Status using Python. In 2018 I left the job and started full time job at Center for Automation and Digitation (CAD). There I have developed many Web Applications using different tools and platforms for education ministry. Here now I am acting as lead application developer as well as Oracle Database Manager, Application Deployment Manager. Some Applications are:

- 1. Personal Data Sheet: Employee Management System for Ministry of Education http://202.72.235.210/pds http://202.72.235.210/pds-admin/
- 2. Educational Institutes Inhouse Training Management: (ex: EIIN 112211) http://202.72.235.210/inhouse-training/
- 3. Educational Institution Details Search: (ex: EIIN 112211) http://202.72.235.217/institute-search
- 4. Annual Educational Survey: http://202.72.235.217
- 5. Educational Information Query and Reporting System: http://202.72.235.210/sebabox
- 6. Primary School Survey PEC: http://202.72.235.210/primary-pec/site/public
- 7. Fitnessplus Gym http://159.65.224.13/gulshan/users/login
- 8. Sher-e-Bangla University Library http://www.saulibrary.edu.bd/new/milestone-link.php